Donnelly, Betty Hawley papers 5393
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Betty Hawley Donnelly papers
1946-1970
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Donnelly, Betty Hawley, 1896-1970
5393
3 cubic feet
4 linear ft.
Photographs.
Correspondence and files of Betty Hawley Donnelly, vice president of the New York Federation of Labor and its successor, the New York State AFL-CIO.
2295989
Biographical / Historical
A vice-president of the New York State AFL-CIO for fifty years and chairman of its committee on education. Donnelly also worked with the N.Y.C. Board of Education for forty years and was a member of the President's and Governor's Committees for the Physically Handicapped.
Scope and Contents
Consist chiefly of correspondence and reports concerning vocational education and health. Include correspondence (1939-1943) with the following: Ernest L. Stebbin (commissioner of health, City of New York), Lester W. Herzog (administrator, Federal Works Agency, Work Projects Administration), Frank Powers (Powers X-Ray Corporation), George F. Pigott (associate superintendent of schools), John E. Wade (superintendent of schools), and Hiram Jones (State Department of Education) regarding the vocational school x-ray survey, tuberculosis, and health programs in the New York vocational high schools; also reports on health instruction, physical examinations, physical fitness, tuberculosis, and the vocational schools chest x-ray survey; letters (1943) from members of the Assembly, State of New York (Albany) regarding the Vocational Schools Health Bill, Assembly PR 1627, Int. 1448; letters (1959-1960) regarding retail marketing in New York City; letters (1965) on Donnelly's retirement; condolence letters to Donnelly's son, John R. Hawley, upon her death (1970); requests for criticisms of curricula for courses in woodworking, carpentry, optical mechanics and retail distribution; and reports of the Committee on Education of the New York State Federation of Labor (1939, 1941, 1956). Also include a report of the New York City Board of Education's Advisory Board on Vocational Education to members of the Governor's Committee on Discrimination (1942); occupational survey of the food trades of the City of New York (1958); reports on job opportunities for electrical workers and automotive engineers; curricula outlines (1962-1963) for courses in food trades, beauty culture, automotive mechanics, sheet metal working, plumbing, machine shop and plastics; financial statements (1958, 1959), and routine letters (1929-1963) of the Petroleum Education Foundation chartered by the Regents of the University of the State of New York; interim report to study vocational education (1940); clippings; photographs; and printed and miscellaneous materials.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 06, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019
Automobiles -- Maintenance and repair -- Study and teaching -- United States; Food service employees -- New York (State) -- New York; Occupational surveys; Occupational training -- New York (State) -- New York; Occupational training -- New York (State); Vocational education -- New York (State) -- New York; Labor leaders; Vocational teachers; Automobile industry -- United States -- Vocational guidance; Beauty culture -- Study and teaching -- United States; Electric industries -- United States -- Vocational guidance; Food service -- Study and teaching -- United States; Machine shops -- United States -- Vocational guidance; Sheet-metal works -- Study and teaching -- United States; Vocational students -- Health and hygiene -- New York (State); New York State AFL-CIO; New York State Federation of Labor; United States. Federal Works Agency; United States. Work Projects Administration; Donnelly, Betty Hawley, 1896-1970; Stebbin, Ernest L.
2295989
- X-Ray Bill: Letters from Legislature, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Appreciation Letters and Reports of Committee on Education, 1938-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Materials on Tuberculosis X-Rays, 1935-1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Photos and publications, 1936-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, articles, publications, 1940-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Retail Marketing Correspondence, 1937, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Condolence Letters, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Petroleum Education Foundation, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8a)
- Petroleum Education Foundation, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8b)
- Food-Maritime School, 1929-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Courses of Study: Committee of 9, 1934-1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1939-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- An Occupational Opportunities Survey of the Food Trades, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Printing News, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Historical Background of the Advisory Board for Vocational and Extension Education, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Award Picture, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Preamble and Resolutions Regarding Tribute to Honorable Betty Hawley Donnelly, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Vocational Education and Guidance in New York City, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Certificate of Appreciation, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Certificates, 1935-1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- New York State Maritime College, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  Certificate
- State of New York Executive Chamber, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 4)